Emmanuel Senft

Curriculum Vitae

CONTACT

Email esenft@wisc.edu

Website https://emmanuel-senft.github.io/index.html

Scholar https://scholar.google.co.uk/citations?user=Yw1tGf4AAAAJ&hl=en citations > 500, h-index = 12

RESEARCH STATEMENT

Robots I want to create rich robotic systems to allow robots to both useful and impactful Learning to in our society. My research is focused on exploring ways to allow robots to learn Interact complex and efficient policies in the real world. I am interested in Human-Robot Interaction both for physical and social interactions, as they encompass traditional challenges of the real world: high cost of failure, limited number of datapoints and real-world application. I believe that combining shared control and interactive machine learning is key to allow robots to safely learn to interact in such sensitive and real environments.

EMPLOYMENT

Current Research Associate, HCI Lab, University of Wisconsin-Madison, USA, PI: Prof. Bilge Mutlu (since Oct 2019).

2019 Cooperate Researcher, JSPS Summer program, IRC - ATR, Japan, PI: Prof. Takayuki Kanda (June-August).

Research Fellow, Plymouth University,, UK, PI: Prof. Tony Belpaeme. part-time (January to March)

2018 Research Assistant, Plymouth University, UK, PI: Prof. Tony Belpaeme.

EDUCATION

2014-2018 PhD, Plymouth University, Plymouth, UK, Title: Teaching Robots Social Autonomy From In Situ Human Supervision.

Supervisory team: Prof. Tony Belpaeme, Dr. Paul Baxter and Dr Séverin Lemaignan

2008–2013 Master of Science in Robotic and Autonomous Systems, Swiss Federal Institute of Technology Lausanne (EPFL), Switzerland, Master thesis with Prof. Auke J. lispeert.

With Minor in Area and Cultural Studies.

AWARD

2019 Queen Mary UK Best PhD in Robotics Award: Second position.

GRANTS

2019 **JSPS Summer Program**: 2 months research program with Prof. Takayuki Kanda at ATR, Japan.

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

Journals

2019 • Teaching robots social autonomy from in situ human guidance.

E. Senft, S. Lemaignan, PE. Baxter, and T. Belpaeme Science Robotics 4 (35)

• Robot-Enhanced Therapy: Development and Validation of a Supervised Autonomous Robotic System for Autism Spectrum Disorders Therapy.

HL. Cao, ..., **E. Senft**, ..., and T. Ziemke IEEE Robotics & Automation Magazine, 2019.

2017 • Supervised Autonomy for Online Learning in Human-Robot Interaction.

E. Senft, P. Baxter, J. Kennedy, S. Lemaignan, and T. Belpaeme Pattern Recognition Letters, 2017.

• How to Build a Supervised Autonomous System for Robot-Enhanced Therapy for Children with Autism Spectrum Disorder.

P.G. Esteban, ..., **E. Senft**, ..., T.Ziemke Paladyn, Journal of Behavioral Robotics. De Gruyter Open, 2017.

Conferences

2020 • Would You Mind Me if I Pass by You? Socially-Appropriate Behaviour for an Omni-based Social Robot in Narrow Environment.

E. Senft, S. Satake and T. Kanda HRI. 2020.

2017 • Child Speech Recognition in Human-Robot Interaction: Evaluations and Recommendations.

B. Irfan, J. Kennedy, S. Lemaignan, F. Papadopoulos, **E. Senft**, and T. Belpaeme HRI, 2017.

2016 • Social Robot Tutoring for Child Second Language Learning.

J. Kennedy, P. Baxter, **E. Senft**, and T. Belpaeme HRI, 2016.

2015 • SPARC: Supervised Progressively Autonomous Robot Competencies.

E. Senft, P. Baxter, J. Kennedy, and T. Belpaeme. ICSR, 2015.

 $\label{list-complete} Complete \ \ \ \, \text{list https://emmanuel-senft.github.io/publication.html} \\ \text{with pdf}$

INVITED TALK

2019 30 Jan CHILI Lab - EPFL (Lausanne, Switzerland)
 14 Feb Robot Learning and Interaction Lab - IDIAP (Martigny, Switzerland)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

since 2017 **Event Organiser**,

AAMAS 2019 (PC member) AAAI Symposium AI-HRI 2017-2019 (Program Chair) HRI Workshop 2019 - Robots in Therapy and Care (Committee member).

since 2015 **Reviewer**, Scientific Reports, JIST, ICRA, HRI, MECH, JHRI, IS, SBLI, IBERDIS-CAP, HAI, ICSR, HUMANOID, RO-MAN, TAROS....

2015-2017 **Demonstrator**, *ROCO 318 - Mobile and Humanoid Robots*, Plymouth University. Leading practical work on bipedal gait design and control for 3rd year students.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Advanced Python, ROS, QML, C++, Machine Learning (ANN, RL, Interactive Machine Learning), Robotics, NaoQi, Human-Robot Interaction, Study Design, Academic Writing, Robot Assisted Therapy (especially for children with ASD).

Intermediate Solidworks, ProEngineer, MatLab, C, JAVA, Pepper and YARP.

LANGUAGES

French Mother tongue

English Advanced Conversationally fluent and technical

Mandarin Basic Level A2
German Basic Level A2

OTHER EXPERIENCE

2016-2017 **Comittee member**, *Karate-UPSU*, Plymouth University, UK. Treasurer for the university karate club. (member from 2014 to 2018)

2007-2013 **Scout Team Leader**, *Eclaireuses et Eclaireurs Unionistes de France de Douvaine*. Team management and leadership, organisation of events with 8-12 or 12-16 years old children with legal responsibility, member from 1998 to 2013.

2008-2012 Member, Robopoly, EPFL, Switzerland. Robotic Association.